Keep your room well-lit.
And don't sit too close to the television.
[Today they are working in a convenience store. The most popular item in the store is the "Tasty Stick".]
[Gin-san, who has a sweet-tooth, always picks chocolate flavor. Don't forget "Bargain Dash Ice Cream" too!]
(神楽)いらっしゃいませよ～｡
Welcome!
(客)いや…
いらっしゃいじゃなくて｡
Never mind the welcome.
Note: "Nmaibo" literally means tasty stick.
If you're working, how come you're eating Nmaibo?
おぬし 勤務中であろう｡
なぜ んまい棒を食べておるのだ｡
Because it's nmai.
んまいからでございますよ～｡
Are you trying to make a fool outta me?
おぬし… 私を ﾅﾒてるだろう｡
(客)おいぃ！ ﾎﾞﾛﾎﾞﾛ ﾎﾞﾛﾎﾞﾛ➡
Hey! You're spilling crumbs into my bag!
食べくずが
袋に入ってるだろうが！
Hey! Where's the store manager?! Manger?!
(客)ちょっ… 店長～！
店長を呼べぇ！
(銀時)店長の 坂田で～す｡
I'm the manager, Sakata. Sir, got a problem?
お客さん
何か問題でもございましたか？
お前たちが 大問題だぁ！
You two are the problem!
おい… なんか
えらい怒ってんじゃねえか｡
Hey, he seems awfully upset. What'd you do?
お前 なにやったんだよ？
わかりません｡ 来たときから➡
I don't know. He's been in a bad mood since he walked in, manager!
ずっと怒っているであります
店長！
Hey! I'm telling you to stop munching on that! Hey!
おい！ そのｻｸｻｸ
やめろって言ってんだよ！
(客)おい！
すみません お客さん｡
Sorry, sir.
ﾎﾞｸら 臨時で入ったものなんで
難しいこと わかんないっす｡
We're temporary help, so we're not too familiar with sophisticated marketing issues.
But we're doing our best, so give us a break.
でも 一生懸命やるんで
よろしくお願いします｡
I don't care if you do your best. I'm just telling to take that stick out of your mouth!
(客)一生懸命
やんなくていいから➡
その棒 取れって言ってんだよ！
(電子ﾚﾝｼﾞのｽｲｯﾁ音)
Hey! What're you microwaving over there?!
(客)おい ちょっと それ
なに あっためてんの!?
I don't know. But I'm working really hard at it, yup!
自分 わかんないっす｡
でも 一生懸命やるっす｡ ｳｯｽ！
Yup?! Hey, my JUMP's in there!
ｳｯｽって… ちょっと
ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟとか入ってんだけど！
あっ！ あぁ～!! 爆発した
なんか爆発した！
Huh?! It exploded! What exploded?!
(客)なにをするか ｷｻﾏ～！
What're you doing, you?! My JUMP is covered with salad dressing!
(客)ｼﾞｬﾝﾌﾟが
ﾄﾞﾚｯｼﾝｸﾞまみれではないか～！
(神楽)自分 わかんないっす｡
でも こんな冷たい時代だから➡
I don't know about that.
But I think it's a good thing to have a cozy convenience store like this in such a cold-hearted era.
こんなｱｯﾄﾎｰﾑなｺﾝﾋﾞﾆがあっても
いいと思うっす！
It's not! Gimme back my money!
(客)いいわけねえだろ！
ﾃﾒｴ 弁償しろ ｺﾗ!!
(新八)ﾊｧ… だから ﾎﾞｸらには
ﾑﾘって言ったんだよ｡
That's why I said it was impossible for us.
((長谷川:いやぁ…
今 知り合いの つてで➡
Say, I'm looking after a convenience store as a favor to my friend.
ｺﾝﾋﾞﾆ 任されてんだけど➡
But I have some business I gotta take care of and can't watch over the store.
ﾔﾎﾞ用で 出れない日が
できちゃって…｡
(長谷川)悪いけど １日 頼むわ｡
ﾎﾝﾄ ごめん！
Sorry, it's only for one day. Thanks so much.
じゃ よろしく～！))
See you!
ﾊｧ… 長谷川さんが
帰ってくる頃には➡
At this rate, by the time Hasegawa-san returns, the shop will be out of business.
店 つぶれてるよ これ｡
なにやってんの ｷﾐ！
What're you doing?
お腹 見せて｡ なんか盗ったろ！
Open your shirts. You stole something, didn't you?
(ﾀｶﾁﾝ)んだよ なんも盗って…｡
What?! I didn't...!
Sh-Shin-chan?
し 新ちゃん…｡
ﾀｶﾁﾝ？
Takachin?
["Don't Be Shy - Just Raise Your Hand and Say It"]
高屋 八兵衛 16歳…
新八と 同じ歳か｡
Hachibei Takaya, age sixteen.  The same as you, Shinpachi.
いい歳して 恥ずかしくねえのか？
母ちゃん 泣くよ お前｡
Aren't you embarrassed? Stealing at your age!
You'll make your mama cry.
だいたいよぉ
こんな たくさんの整髪料➡
Besides, what were you planning to do with so much hair styling gel?
どうするつもりだったんだ？
Quit worrying about your hair and be more confident about yourself!
心配しないでも きまってるよ｡
お前 自分に自信をもて！
Like I was gonna use all of this myself!
これ全部
ｵﾚが使うわけねえだろうが！
じゃ なんだ？ ご飯か？
Then what? A condiment?
Were you planning to pour it over your rice so you could eat silky, luxuriant food?
ご飯にかけて
ｻﾗｻﾗ いくつもりだったのか？
ｹｯ…｡
Takachin, why'd you do such a thing?
ﾀｶﾁﾝ… なんで こんなこと…｡
ﾀｶﾁﾝ こんなことするﾔﾂじゃ
なかったじゃないか｡
Takachin, you didn't used to be like this.
うっせえよ｡ あれから
何年経ったと思ってんだ｡
Shut up! How many years do you think have passed?
ｵﾚは もう ｵﾒｴの知ってる
ﾀｶﾁﾝじゃねえんだよ｡
I'm not the Takachin you used to know.
もういいから 番所でも
奉行所でも➡
So just take me wherever...to the police station or the magistrate.
どこでも 連れてけや｡
磔 獄門 上等だ この野郎！
And if they wanna crucify me, fine!
(ﾀｶﾁﾝ)恩でも売ったつもりか？
ﾃﾒｴ｡
Don't expect me to be grateful.
また来てやっかんな｡
I'll just come back again.
そのときは またﾎﾞｸが止めるよ｡
And I'll stop you again.
ｹｯ 相変わらずの お人よしだな➡
Sheesh, still the same goody-two-shoes, eh? Shin-chan.
新ちゃんよぉ…｡
(騒ぎ声)
((新八:ﾀｶﾁﾝを離せ！))
Leave Takachin alone!
(ﾀｶﾁﾝ)一緒に寺子屋に
通ってた頃も➡
When we were at Temple school together, you and your sister always came to my rescue.
ｵﾚが いじめられてたら➡
よく ｵﾒｴら 姉弟が
助けてくれたもんだ｡
((ﾀｶﾁﾝ:新ちゃん…｡
Shin-chan!
We'll make you cry too!
(悪ｶﾞｷ)ﾌﾝｯ！
(悪ｶﾞｷ)ｷｻﾏも 泣かしてやる！
うらうら 泣け！
誰が 泣くもんか！
Go ahead and cry!
I will not! I'm a samurai's son!
ﾎﾞｸは 侍の子だぁ！
(お妙)なに さらしとんじゃ ﾜﾚ！
ﾊｯ!!))
What's the big idea, you bullies!
(ﾀｶﾁﾝ)まっ ほとんど
ｵﾒｴの姉ちゃんが➡
Well, it was mostly your sister creating a scene.
暴れてただけだけどよ｡
懐かしいもんだ… ﾌｯ｡
Brings back memories.
お前だけは 何があっても
友達だと思ってた｡
I thought you'd be my friend, no matter what happened.
あのとき 裏切られるまではよぉ｡
Until that day that you betrayed me.
ﾀｶﾁﾝ あれは…｡
Takachin, that was...
I don't wanna hear your excuses!
言い訳なんて 聞きたかねえな｡
ﾃﾒｴの 半端な優しさで➡
Do you know how much I suffered because of your half-assed attempt at kindness?!
ｵﾚが どんだけ傷ついたと
思ってんだ？ ああ!?
あれから ｵﾚは…｡
Ever since that day, I...
ﾁｯ… まぁ いいさ｡
Well, forget it.
ﾃﾒｴのおかげで ｵﾚも
少しは たくましくなれた｡
Thanks to you, I got a little stronger.
今 ｵﾚ 族に入ってんだ｡
I'm in a gang now.
知ってるか？ ｢舞流独愚｣ってよ｡
Heard of them? The Bulldogs?
もう ﾃﾒｴの力なんて 必要ねえ｡
I don't need to rely on your strength anymore. I'm strong now!
ｵﾚは 強くなったんだ！
(お妙)ﾀｶﾁﾝｺ？ だぁれ？ それ｡
Takachinko? Who's that?
[Note: Chinko means penis.]
いや… ﾀｶﾁﾝｺじゃなくてﾀｶﾁﾝです｡
Not Takachinko. Takachin.
ﾎﾝﾄに覚えてないんですか？
You really don't remember?
(お妙)昔のことは 忘れたわ｡
I've forgotten about the past.
私… 前だけ見て
生きていくことに決めたの｡
I've decided to be more forward-thinking.
そんなことより 皆さんに
差し入れ 持ってきたんですよ｡
But never mind that. I brought you all a treat.
銀さんも 神楽ちゃんも
食べてください｡
Gin-san, Kagura-san, please help yourselves.
うわぁ～い！ ｱﾈｺﾞ!!
Yay! Big sis!
今回は 新しい料理に
挑戦してみたんです｡
I tried making something new.
(お妙)はい だし巻き卵｡
Here you go. Rolled omelets.
I'll go and get some drinks!.
私 飲み物 買ってくるよ！
Never mind. I'll go, you sit!
いいって！
ｵﾚが行くから 座ってろ！
ここは ｺﾝﾋﾞﾆよ｡ 飲み物なら
そこに腐るほど あるわ｡
This is a convenience store. You can find all the drinks you need right here.
女に 恥をかかせるものじゃ
ありません｡
You mustn't embarrass a girl like that.
新ちゃん あなたも
こっちに来て 食べなさい｡
Shin-chan, come here and eat. It's very good.
おいしいから｡
新ちゃん…？
姉上…｡
Shin-chan...?
Sister...
たしか 舞流独愚っていえば➡
Without a doubt, the Bulldogs are the rowdiest gang around.
ここいらで いちばん
ﾀﾁの悪い連中ですよね｡
ｹﾝｶだの 盗みだの
平気でやる連中だって｡
They fight and steal without a care.
新ちゃん… あなた そんなに
ﾀｶﾁﾝﾎﾟのことが…｡
[Note: Chinpo also means penis.]
Shin-chan, why are you so concerned about Takachinpo.
ﾀｶﾁﾝです 姉上｡
It's Takachin, Sister.
ﾀｶﾁﾝが あんなになったのは
ﾎﾞｸのせいなんです｡
It's my fault that Takachin turned that way. I turned my back on him.
ﾎﾞｸは 彼を 突き放したんだ…｡
彼が いちばん困ってるときに…｡
When he was at his lowest point...
((しっ 新ちゃん… どうしよう｡
Sh-Shin-chan, what'll I do? I pooped my pants.
ｳﾝｺ もらしちゃった…｡
ねぇ どうしよう… 新ちゃんてば｡
What'll I do, Shin-chan?
ｸﾞｰ ｸﾞｰ…｡
新ちゃん ﾎﾝﾄは 起きてんでしょ？
Shin-chan, I'll bet you're really awake.
ｸﾞｰ ｸﾞｰ…｡
Shin-chan, Shin-chan!
新ちゃん… 新ちゃんてば！))
青春なんて 砂の城ですよ｡
The springtime of youth is like a sandcastle. The smallest thing can make it crumble.
ほんの 些細なことで
すべて 崩れ落ちてしまう｡
あれから すぐ ﾎﾞｸは
借金のせいで➡
Right after that, I stopped going to the Temple school due to family debts.
寺子屋に 通えなくなったけど➡
ﾀｶﾁﾝが そのあと
どんな生活を送ったか➡
But it's not hard to imagine Takachin's life after that.
簡単に想像できますよ｡
あのとき ﾎﾞｸは
どうすればよかったんですかね｡
What should I have done back then?
どうすれば ﾀｶﾁﾝを
救えたんですかね｡
How could I have answered Takachin's call?
いやいや いや… ﾑﾘだろう｡
No, no. That was a hopeless case.
ﾑﾘ ﾑﾘ｡
(お妙)ﾑﾘじゃないわ｡
Yes, totally hopeless.
No, it wasn't.
友達が 泣いているときは
一緒に泣いてあげればいい｡
When your friend is crying, cry with him.
友達が悩んでいるときは➡
When your friend is worried, you should worry with him.
一緒に 頭 抱えて
悩んであげればいい｡
友達が 脱糞したときは…➡
When your friend has an awkward bowel movement...
一緒に あなたも
脱糞しなさい 新ちゃん｡
then you must have a bowel movement too, Shin-chan.
(お妙)友達なら どんな痛みも
分け合うことができるのよ｡
If you are a friend, you should be able to share the other's pain, no matter what.
(お妙)そしてね 新ちゃん｡
And Shin-chan, if your friend goes down the wrong path...
(お妙)もし 友達が
間違った道に➡
進んでしまったときは…➡
そのときは 友情を壊してでも
友達を止めなさい｡
Then, you must stop your friend, even if it ruins your friendship.
それが 真の侍の友情よ｡
That is true samurai friendship.
♪♪～
すみません 店長｡
Excuse me, manager. I have some business to take care of. Please excuse me.
用事がありますので
早退させてもらいます｡
おいおい いいのかよ？
Hey, hey, are you sure about this?
You never know what the youth will do these days.
最近のｶﾞｷは 何するか
わかったもんじゃねえぜ｡
どうなっても知らねえぞ｡
Don't come crying to me if something happens.
(ｸﾗｸｼｮﾝ)
♪♪～
ﾍﾍﾍﾍﾍ！
[Bulldog]
(平蔵)この役立たず！
You useless idiot! Who said to get regular-hold mousse?!
誰が ｵﾒｴ 普通のﾑｰｽ
盗ってこいったよ ｵﾒｴ！
ぐっ！
I told you, didn't I?
(平蔵)ｵﾚの髪は ｵﾒｴ
超ﾊｰﾄﾞﾑｰｽでねえと➡
I need extra control styling mousse to hold my hair in place!
ｾｯﾄできねえって
言ったろうが！ あぁ!?
すみません…｡
I-I'm sorry. I ran into a little trouble.
ちょっと
ｼﾞｬﾏが入っちまいまして…｡
ﾃﾒｴよぉ どうしても
ｳﾁ入りてえっていうから➡
You begged me to let you to join the gang, so I made an exception!
しかたなく
入れてやったってのによ｡
But if you can't even do a simple errand, what's the use?
お使いもできねえんじゃ
話にならんぜ｡
ちょっと 気合い入れる必要が
ありそうだな 気合いをよ｡
I think I need to beat some of that fighting spirit into you, right? Some spirit.
(ﾀｶﾁﾝ)なんすか これ！
Wh-What's this?!
何するつも…｡
Hey, what're you doing?!
(ﾀｶﾁﾝ)うっ… うわぁ～っ!!
Hachibei, we'll give you some fighting spirit!
八兵衛 気合いだ 気合い！
(ﾀｶﾁﾝ)うわぁ～っ!!
…ん？
ぐわぁっ！
(平蔵)な… なんだ!?
Wh-Wha--?!
誰だ ﾃﾒｴ！
Who the hell are you?!
ｵﾚが誰か だと？
Who am I? You must be some amateur if you don't know who I am.
ｵﾚを知らんとは ﾓｸﾞﾘか ｷｻﾏら｡
ｵﾚは 寺門 通 親衛隊 隊長
志村 新八だ！
I am the President of the Otsu-chan Fan Club, Shinpachi Shimura!
し… 新ちゃん…｡
Sh-Shin-chan...
なんで こんなところにいんだよ？
What're you doing here?! This is no place for you!
ここは お前なんかの
来るところじゃねえ！
Go home!
(ﾀｶﾁﾝ)帰れ！
すみません！
Excuse me!
このなかの頭は 誰ですか？
Who's your leader?
Huh? As if our Chairman would see a guy like you!
あぁ？ 総長が ﾃﾒｴなんかに
会うわけねえだろ｡
なんだ 小僧｡ なんの用だ？ ﾃﾒｴ｡
So, kid? Whaddya want?
高屋 八兵衛を 引き取りにきた｡
I'm here to take Hachibei Takaya back.
彼は 今日この時をもって
舞流独愚を脱退し➡
From this moment on, he is resigning from the Bulldogs and joining the Otsu-chan Fan Club!
お通ちゃんﾌｧﾝｸﾗﾌﾞに
入会してもらう｡
その許可が欲しい｡
I came to get your permission.
(ﾀｶﾁﾝ)なに
勝手なこと言ってんだ！
Wh-What're you saying?! Otsu-chan Fan Club? What the hell is that? I...
(ﾀｶﾁﾝ)なんだ
お通ちゃんﾌｧﾝｸﾗﾌﾞって！ ｵﾚは…｡
ﾀｶﾁﾝ… ﾎﾞｸも ﾀｶﾁﾝと一緒だよ｡
Takachin. I'm just like you.
Since that crap incident, I've been sick of my weakness, and I've wanted to become stronger.
あのｳﾝｺ事件以来
自分の弱さがｲﾔで➡
ずっと
強くなりたいって思ってた｡
But Takachin, there's no shortcut to becoming strong.
でも ﾀｶﾁﾝ…
強くなるための近道なんて ない｡
外見だけ 強く装ったって➡
Even if you try to look strong, appearances eventually wear off.
そんなﾊﾘﾎﾞﾃ
すぐに はがれ落ちてしまう｡
徒党を組んだり
強いものの威を借りたり➡
Joining a gang and hiding behind the ferocity of some other guy's strength...
そんなものが
ﾀｶﾁﾝの求めてた強さなの？
Is that the kind of strength you want?
そんな かっこ悪いﾔﾂに
ﾀｶﾁﾝは なりたかったの？
Do you really want to be like these uncool guys?
(下っ端)小僧 悪いがな➡
Kid! Sorry, but this gang ain't no social club.
ｳﾁは 仲よしこよしで
こんなことしてんじゃねえんだ｡
辞めます はい そうですか なんて
簡単にいく組織じゃねえんだよ！
This ain't the kind of organization where you can just say "I quit." And we just say "Oh, okay then."
だったら
力ずくでも 連れていきます｡
In that case, I'll take him by force.
おい！
あんまりﾅﾒんじゃねえぞ ｸｿｶﾞｷが｡
Hey, don't underestimate us, brat!
たった一人で
何ができるってんだ！
And what makes you think you can do anything alone!
１人じゃねえぞ！
He's not alone!
隊長～ やっぱ ﾊﾞｲﾄなんて➡
Hey Chief, part-time work is a pain in the ass! I couldn't stand it.
かったるくて
やってられませんわ｡
あっ！
(お妙)ｹﾝｶなら ｱﾀｲらも混ぜな！
If it's a fight you want, then we'll join in!
The Otsu-chan Fan Club Special Attack Squad "Maltese" has arrived!
寺門 通 親衛隊 特攻部隊
魔流血頭 見参！
そういうことで
そこんとこ 夜露死苦｡
Pleased to make your acquaintance.
[Maltese(?) Please verify.]
♪♪～
(総長)あれ？ これ…➡
Hey... My hairline looks unnatural today.
生え際 いつもより ちょっと
不自然じゃねえ？
Geez, what if it falls off while I'm galloping along?
これ お前… 走ってるときに
ｽﾎﾟｰﾝって取れたら どうなんだろ｡
今まで築いてきたもん
全部 ﾊﾟｰだな｡
My carefully built reputation will be in ruins, that's for sure.
あ～あ… 若い頃から
ﾏｹﾞ染めたり ﾊﾟｰﾏあてたり➡
Oh well, I overdid it when I was younger... All the hair dyes and permaments.
ﾑﾁｬやりすぎたなぁ｡
はぁ… やっぱり
今日も 接着剤でつけとく…｡
I guess I'll just have to glue it on today.
(平蔵)総長！
Chairma-a-a-an!
ﾊﾞﾊﾞﾊﾞﾊﾞﾊﾞｯｷｬﾛ～！
ﾉｯｸくらい しろ！
Y-You idiot!! At least knock first, okay?
すみません！
…え？ ﾉｯｸって どこですれば？
S-Sorry!
Huh? Where should I have knocked?
心のﾉｯｸだ ﾊﾞｶ野郎！ 何の用だ？
Knock in your heart! What do you want?
いや それが
大変なんです 総長！
We've got trouble!! A bunch of guys came to fight and they're crazy strong!
化け物みてえに強え連中が
乗り込んできて…｡
(神楽)ほわちゃ～！
(お妙)はぁっ！
だぁっ！
ｽﾄﾗｯｼｭ！
Slaaaash!
(総長)ﾃﾒｴら なにしてんだ！
(族たち)総長！
What're you jerks doing?!
Chairman!
何でも暴力で解決すんなって
言ったろうが｡
I keep telling you, don't settle everything with violence!
なんだ こりゃ｡ 何があった？
What's going on? What happened?
総長… 総長の頭も
何かあったみたいですよ｡
Chairman... I think something happened to your head.
(総長)江戸で 最強 最速を誇る
舞流独愚を➡
Just the four of you taking on the Bulldogs? Edo's strongest and fastest gang?
たった４人で 相手にしようたぁ…
ﾃﾒｴら 何者だ？
Who are you guys?
あん？ ｵﾚたちは あの…
あれ？ あれだ ｺﾗｧ｡
Huh? We're the...you know. Special Force...um...what was it?
特攻部隊… えぇ…
なんだっけ？ ｺﾗｧ｡
Huh? Special Force Pomeranian... Wasn't that it?
えっ？ 特攻部隊…➡
保女羅尼暗じゃ
なかったかしら ｺﾗｧ｡
Yeah, something like that. Let's use that.
あぁ… なんか そんなんだ｡
それでいくか ｺﾗｧ｡
魔流血頭だよ｡
It's Maltese. At least remember our gang name.
ﾁｰﾑの名前くらい 覚えとこうよ｡
Oh yeah! We're the Malcheese!
あっ そうだ…｡ 魔流血頭だ ｺﾗｧ！
丸かいて 中に三角ﾁｰｽﾞだ｡
ﾅﾒんなよ！
A circle with a triangular piece of cheese.
Don't mess with us!
いや ﾏﾙﾁｰｽﾞ ﾅﾒんなって
言われてもな…｡
Huh? "Don't mess with Maltese"? I don't get it...
Never heard of you. What do you want anyway?!
んなﾁｰﾑ 聞いたことねえぜ｡
いったい 何の用だ？
ﾀｶﾁﾝを 引き取りにきた！
We're taking Takachin with us! I won't let you force my friend to shoplift!
もう ﾎﾞｸの友達に
盗みなんて させない！
ﾀｶﾁﾝ？ ｳﾁのﾁｰﾑに
そんなﾔﾂいたか？
Takachin? Do we have a member named that?
えぇ こないだ入った
高屋のことです｡
Yes. They mean Takaya, the one who just joined up recently.
And? Where is he?
それで？ その高屋は？
あれです｡
Over there.
Hey! What're you doing?!
おい！ なにしてんだぁ!!
え？ これが ﾀｶﾁﾝｺ？
間違えちゃったぜ｡
Huh? This is Takachinko? My mistake, dude... Dammit!
ざけんじゃねえよ！
Don't mess with me!
How could you make a mistake?!
間違えちゃったぜ じゃ
ないっつの～!!
だって みんな
頭に ﾌﾗﾝｽﾊﾟﾝ載っけて➡
Well, everyone's hair looks like a baguette. I couldn't tell the difference.
見分けつかないｱﾙよ｡
おい！
Hey!
ﾒｶﾞﾈ お前 高屋の連れか？
Four-eyes, are you Takaya's friend? I get it.
なるほど 友達 更正させようと
乗り込んだわけか｡ 気に入ったぜ｡
You came here to rehabilitate your buddy, eh?
I like that.
(総長)そんな小物
連れていきたきゃ 連れていけ｡
You want that small fry in your gang. Okay, take him.
しかし 総長！
But Chairman!
But, I want you to do something, first.
ただし その前に
やってもらうことがある｡
ｵﾚたちのﾁｰﾑでは ｶﾀｷﾞに戻る前に
ある儀式をやることになってる｡
We have a ceremony one has to undergo before leaving the gang.
In his current condition, Takaya can't do it.
だが そのｻﾞﾏじゃ 高屋は ﾑﾘ｡
代わりに ﾃﾒｴらに
やってもらおうか｡
You guys are gonna do it for him.
(総長)ﾙｰﾙは 簡単だ｡
ﾊﾞｲｸで 町のはずれにある➡
The rules are simple.
You ride motorbikes to the edge of town... to the freeway that's under construction.
工事中の高架道路まで
突っ走って➡
ｵﾚたちより先に着けば
高屋の ﾁｰﾑ脱退を許してやる｡
If you get there first, I'll let you take Takaya.
武器の使用 相手ﾁｰﾑへの妨害
何でもあり｡
Anything goes. Using weapons, interfering with the opposing team, whatever.
(総長)まぁ １人が運転➡
If I was you, I'd have one of ya ride and the other one attack and obstruct.
１人が 妨害工作にまわるのが
ｵｽｽﾒだな｡
(総長)ちなみに ﾃﾒｴらは
全員 参加してもらうぞ｡
All of you have to race. And we'll have four from our team.
(総長)ｳﾁも ４人出すから｡
Excuse me. We only have one scooter. Can you lend us one, creep?
すみませ～ん 私たち
原ﾁｬﾘ １台しかないんですけど➡
貸してくれませんか？ ｺﾗｧ｡
(総長)お前ら
ﾎﾝﾄに 暴走族なのか？
Are you really a bike gang?!
当たり前だ この野郎｡
地球に優しい暴走族なんだよ ｺﾗｧ｡
Damn right, we are! We're eco-friendly rabble-rousers!
I guess we have no choice.
(総長)しかたねえな｡
あれ？ 姉上
運転できましたっけ？
Huh? Sis, you can drive this thing?
A samurai does not concern himself with petty details, dude.
侍が細かいことを
気にするんじゃありません ｺﾗｧ｡
Gin-chan, I need to go to the little girl's room.
銀ちゃん 私
ｵｼｯｺしたくなってきたｱﾙ｡
どっか その辺でしてこい ｺﾗｧ｡
Then go take a leak over there someplace, dude.
What a thing to tell a lady!
(神楽)ﾚﾃﾞｨｰに向かって
なんてこと言うｱﾙ！
(総長)ﾍﾍ…
おもしろくなりそうだ｡
Heh-heh, this is gonna be interesting.
(ﾃﾞﾌﾞ)それじゃ いきますよ！
Okay, get ready!
Ready...get...set... Go Bull...
にっちもさっちもどうにも
ﾌﾞﾙﾄﾞｯｸﾞ～!!
...dogs!
(銃声)
(みんな)うお～っ!!
♪♪～
(平蔵)ﾌﾝ！ ﾊﾞｶどもが来た来た！
The fools, here they come!
このﾚｰｽ自体が 裏切り者を
制裁するための➡
They have no idea this is a bloody ceremony to punish traitors!
血の儀式とも知らねえで！
ﾊｯﾊﾊ～！
(平蔵)ﾃﾒｴらは みんな
ここで 死ぬんだよ！
You're all gonna die here!
(平蔵)やれ！
Do it!
ﾍﾟｼｬﾝｺに…｡
Flatten 'em!
(神楽)うお～っ!!
(平蔵)えっ!?
平蔵～っ!!
誰が死ぬって？
Heizo!
Who's gonna die, Heizo-chan?
平蔵ちゃんよ～！
ﾇﾊﾊﾊﾊ…!!
銀ちゃん もうｵｼｯｺ 限界！
Gin-chan, I can't hold it anymore.
Go ahead and pee.
もらせ もらせ！ ﾇﾊﾊﾊ！
♪♪～
(２人)あぁ～っ!!
That's the power of our ultra moisturizer! Just lie there and grovel!
(松太郎)
特製ﾛｰｼｮﾝの威力を見たか！
そこで 一生へばってな！
野郎～！ あっ！
Why you--!
なっ なに？
仲間 踏み台にした！
Wh-What?!
She used her teammate as a springboard!
姉上 なんてことすんですかぁ！
Sis, what're you doing?! You probably just killed Gin-san! Hey!
銀さん
あれ 死んじゃったよ たぶん！
ねえ!!
私の前は 何人たりとも➡
I won't allow anybody to pass me!
走らせないわ！
私は 風！ 風になる ｷｬﾊ～！
I am the wind! Born free like the wind! Yahoo!
Huh?! Sis! Did you pass into another dimension or something?
あれ？ 姉上 なんか
違う世界の扉 開いちゃった？
あ～ 気持いい！
あと３ｷﾛくらい出せば➡
It feels so good!
If we speed up by three kilometers, I think we could travel through time!
ﾀｲﾑｽﾘｯﾌﾟできる気がするわ～！
Sis! Time travel on your own time, okay?
姉上 ﾀｲﾑｽﾘｯﾌﾟは
１人でしてください！
それより ﾊﾝﾄﾞﾙ！ ﾊﾝﾄﾞﾙ握って!!
First, the handle bars! Grab the handle bars!
(松太郎)おらぁ～！
これ以上は 行かせねえぞ！
You're not going to pass us!
舞流独愚の恐ろしさを思い知れ!!
I'll show you how frightening we Bulldogs are!
ぶっ！
おま 何さらしとんじゃあ！
What're you doing?! I have three kilometers more to go! Don't interfere!
あと３ｷﾛなんだよ
ｼﾞｬﾏすんじゃねえ!!
Hey, the handle bars! The handle bars!
ﾊﾝﾄﾞﾙ ﾊﾝﾄﾞﾙ!!
やばい やばい あっ！
Hey, no! Don't!
おっ？
ああ～…｡
あわわわ…!!
あ～っ ﾊﾝﾄﾞﾙが!!
姉上 しっかりしてください！
He's bald!
Sister, snap out of it! It wasn't real!
違いますって！
本物じゃないですよ！
ﾂﾞﾗですって それ！
It's just a wig!
あぁ なんてことだ｡
髪の毛が引き抜かれて➡
Whoa! What happened! All my hair got pulled out, and now it looks like I'm bald!
こんなことに
なってしまったぞ｡
Why are you over explaining it like that?
(松太郎)なんで説明口調？
ま 松太郎…｡
Hey Matsutaro, is there anything you want?
お前 何かほしいものあるか？
総長… 心配しなくても
総長の頭の件は➡
Chairman, don't worry. Everyone's known about your hair condition for a long time.
みんなに とっくにﾊﾞﾚﾊﾞﾚです｡
ｳｿ…!?
Oh no! Seriously?
うぅ…！
(神楽)新八～！
Shinpachi!
もう少しの辛抱ある！
気張り～!!
Just hang in there a little longer! Hang on!
おりゃあ～!!
What the hell is this brat?!
(総長)なんじゃ このｶﾞｷ～!?
(神楽)ﾑﾊﾊﾊﾊ！
暴走族がなんぼのもんじゃ！
こちとら 人生という道を➡
What's the big deal with rabble rousing biker gangs?!
I've been raising hell all my life!
暴走しとんじゃい！
格の違いを見せたれ 銀ちゃん！
Show 'em we're in a totally different class, Gin-chan!
Who is that?!
誰だ？ それ～!!
あ～！ 銀ちゃんが！
It's Gin-chan!
だから お酒と いちご牛乳は
控えろって言ったのによ～！
That's why I told him to switch the sake with strawberry milk!
Don't blame the sake! Your head's to blame!
酒のせいじゃねえ！
悪いのは お前の頭だ!!
ﾊｯﾊﾊﾊ…
お前ら 暴走族なんかより➡
You guys are better as comedians than a biker gang!
漫才師にでもなったほうが
いいんじゃねえの？
Oh yeah?
そうかい？
お前のほうは
確実に向いてそうだけどな｡
Looks like you're the comedian! What with your fly away wig and all!
その頭の飛び道具は 使えるぜ｡
ﾃﾒｴ！
銀さん！
Why you--!
Gin-san!
あの娘は 囮か？
Was that girl just a decoy? You pulled my attention offa you...
注意を他に向けさせ その隙に…｡
このまま
必殺侍ｼﾞｬｰﾏﾝｽｰﾌﾟﾚｯｸｽを決めて➡
I could send you straight to hell right now with my Special Samurai German Suplex.
地獄に送ってやってもいいが➡
それじゃ
新八の心意気に水を差す｡
But that would dampen Shinpachi's enthusiasm.
こっからは 正々堂々➡
So from this point on, you'll race our captain fair and square!
ｳﾁの大将と
やりあってもらおうじゃねえか！
新八！
一丁 決めてこい！
Shinpachi! Go on and win this one for us.
ｵｯｽ！
Right!
Cripes!
(下っ端)ったくよ！
物好きな野郎もいたもんだよ！
What a pain in the ass!
(下っ端)お前みたいな役立たず➡
What's the point of rescuing a useless idiot like you?
助けても
なんの得もねえってのによ！
かわいそうに 今頃
くたばってるかもしれねえぞ｡
Poor guy, he could be dead by now.
Yup, there's never been anyone who lived through this ceremony.
ああ… 今まで
無事だったﾔﾂなんて➡
いねえからよ！
逃げ出したんじゃねえか？
Maybe they ran away.
(笑い声)
(下っ端)それは ありだな｡
総長に土下座して➡
That's possible. Maybe they groveled before the Chairman and begged for forgiveness.
許してもらってよ！
ぐぐぅっ…！
ああっ！
(急ﾌﾞﾚｰｷ音)
♪♪～
(下っ端)遅えな～！
They're late.
こりゃ 本格的に
ﾊﾞｯｸﾚちまったんじゃねえか！
Maybe they really are dead.
(蹴る音)
(ﾀｶﾁﾝ)うっ！
何とか言え おらおら！
Say something!
ﾊｯﾊﾊﾊ… 所詮
ﾃﾒｴの ﾀﾞﾁだもんなぁ｡
They're your friends, after all.
速攻 ﾊﾞｯｸﾚたに決まってらぁ｡
No doubt they're all dead.
(下っ端)そうそう 類は友を呼ぶ｡
Right. Flies attract flies. A scumbag is bound to have scumbag friends!
ｸｽﾞのﾀﾞﾁも ｸｽﾞだろ！
(笑い声)
Hey, look.
(下っ端)ん？ おい あれ！
なんだ？
What?
♪♪～
(下っ端)おい ｳｿだろ？
(下っ端)まさか➡
No way!
Don't tell me he made it through all the traps!
あの罠 乗り越えてきたってのか？
(下っ端)ﾊﾞｲｸは どうしたんだ？
あの距離➡
What about the bike?! He ran the whole way?!
ずっと走ってきたってのか？
Never mind the bike! The Chairman doesn't have his wig!
(下っ端)ﾊﾞｲｸどころか
総長にいたっては ﾂﾞﾗもねえぜ！
ﾊｧ ﾊｧ ﾊｧ…！
Takachin... I'm just like you, Takachin.
《ﾀｶﾁﾝ… ﾎﾞｸも ﾀｶﾁﾝと一緒だよ｡
自分の弱さが嫌いで ずっと
強くなりたかった｡
I hated my own weakness... and I always wanted to be strong...
だから！》
That's why...
(２人)ﾊｧ ﾊｧ ﾊｧ…！
(総長)ああっ！
♪♪～
ﾊｧ ﾊｧ ﾊｧ ﾊｧ…｡
You fool...
(ﾀｶﾁﾝ)この ﾊﾞｶ野郎が…｡
♪♪～
Damn, thanks for nothing.
(ﾀｶﾁﾝ)ったく
勝手なことしてくれやがって｡
Do you know how hard it was for me to join that gang?
ｵﾚが あのﾁｰﾑに入るの
どれだけ苦労したと思ってんだ？
罪滅ぼしのつもりかなんか
知らねえけど➡
So you tried to make amends. Well, it's too late.
今さら 遅えっつうの｡
はいはい わかったって…｡
All right, I get it.
Listen, I'm not forgiving you, ever!
(ﾀｶﾁﾝ)いいか！ 何やったって
ｵﾚは お前 許さねえからよ｡
だから もう
あんなこと すんなよな｡
So don't pull anything like that again.
迷惑だから…｡
ﾀｶﾁﾝ…｡
さっきだって ｵﾒｴ…➡
Takachin...
Back there... the chairman said he was impressed with your spirit.
総長が ｵﾒｴの根性に
惚れたっつってよ…➡
ﾁｰﾑに ｵﾒｴを入れるって
大変だったんだからよ～｡
He was gonna make you join the gang! Turning him down was a hassle.
断るのに ひと苦労よ｡
I had to explain that I couldn't let my friend get mixed up in something like that.
(ﾀｶﾁﾝ)友達にそんなこと
させるわけには いかねえってな｡
はいはい… よく言うよ｡
Okay, okay. I hear you.
I've got to stop asking those jerks for help.
もう ｱｲﾂらに
頼みごとすんのは やめよう…｡
[Preview]
What's this?
Otsu-chan! Popular idol singer turned fighter!
When a person says something like that, it's a warning sign.
My favorite ramen shop once said, "Why don't we try serving curry?"
After that, the shop had to close.
The next episode: "Some Things Can't Be Cut with a Sword."
[Antonio Kagura breaks in to the "Amazons Tournament"!]
[Gintoki and Shinpachi try to leave acting like they don't know anything. But they meet someone unexpected.]
Just bring it from anywhere, jock itch!
Okay, next show is by those two guys, King Kong. Thank you.
(お通)どこからでも
かかってきなさいﾝｷﾝﾀﾑｼ～!!